California ephemera collection, 1860-
California Ephemera Collection,
- Mason, Biddy, 1818 - 1891 (Boxes 253, 253)
  - Grandma Biddy: Biddy Mason's Place, a midwife's homestead., c1988.; Item No. 1 (Box 197, Folder 3)
    Includes biographical information by Hayden, photographs and quotes by Biddy Mason and other ex-slaves. Includes bibliographical references. Also includes some of Biddy Mason's remedies.
- Massage therapy (Box 244)
- Mather, Margrethe, 1885(?) - 1952 (Box 67)
- May, Cliff (Box 67)
  1. Architects - California. 2. Architecture - California, Southern.
- Mayors - California - Los Angeles (Box 67)
- Maywood Colony, Tehama County (Box 67)
- McAleer, Owen (Box 66)
- McClure, Michael, 1932 - (Box 66)
- McDaniel, Hattie (Box 244)
- McDonald, Patrick J., 1863 - 1941 (Box 66)
- McDonald's Restaurants (Box 197)
  Map of southern California.
- McDougal, John, - 1866 (Box 66)
  1.McDougal, John, - 1866 - portrait.
- McEnerney, Garret W., 1865 - 1942 (Box 66)
- McGroarty, John Steven, 1862 - 1944 (Box 66)
- McIntosh, Charles Kenneth, 1867 - (Box 66)
  1. McIntosh, Charles Kenneth, 1867 - portrait.
- McIntyre, Robert, 1851 - 1914 (Box 66)
  1. McIntyre, Robert, 1851 - 1914 - portrait.
- McKenna, Joseph, 1843 - 1926 (Box 66)
  1. McKenna, Joseph, 1843 - 1926 - portrait.
- McKinlay, Duncan E., 1862 - 1914 (Box 66)
- McLachlan, James, 1852 - 1940 (Box 66)
- McNaghten, Malcolm (Box 66)
  1. McNaghten, Malcolm - portrait.
- McPherson, Aimee Semple, 1890 - 1944 (Box 66)
- McPherson, James Gordon (Box 66)
- McQuilling, Adam K., 1840 - 1940 (Box 67)
- McReynolds, Frances (Coulter), 1882? - 1942 (Box 67)
  X. Coulter, Frances.
- Meals on Wheels. West Los Angeles. (Box 196)
- Medical care - California (Box 68)
- Medical societies (Box 68)
- Melrose Square Publishing Co. Los Angeles, California. (Box 195)
- Mendell, George Henry, 1831 - 1902 (Box 68)
- Mendocino County, California (Box 129)
- Merced County, California (Box 68)
- Merriam, Frank F. (Boxes 169, 213)
  Box 169 - 2 folders.
- Metcalf, Victor Howard, 1853 - 1936 (Box 68)
  1. Metcalf, Victor Howard, 1853 - 1936 - portrait.
- Metreon Sony Entertainment Center. San Francisco, California (Box 284)
- Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer. Culver City, California (Box 244)
- Metrolink (Boxes 211, 271)
- Metropolitan University, Los Angeles (Box 68)
- Metropolitan Water District of Southern California (Boxes 68, 284)
- Mexican-Americans - California (Boxes 68, 199, 284)
  - Introduction of the Cultural Children's Movement Aztlan of California., 1973.; Item No. 1 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    Flier advertising a grass-roots Chicano organization for Mexican American children. The flier advocates freedom from "white executives" and "coconut" leaders from the broader community.
  - Plaza de la Raza., 1971.; Item No. 2 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    Brochure advertising construction of Plaza de la Raza, a community and art center with a Chicano and Mexican American theme in Lincoln Park, Los Angeles.
  - Step-children of a nation: the status of Mexican-Americans., 1947.; Item No. 3 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    A report on the status of Mexican Americans for the Panel on Discrimination of the National Conference for Protection of Foreign Born, 1947 (Cleveland, Ohio).
  - The latest moves in the Chicano community: where do we go from here?., May 8, 1971.; Item No. 4 (Folder 1)
    Broadside advertising a community meeting featuring speakers Mauricio Terrazas and Clara James. The discussion and question and answer session will focus on the activities of the Chicano community.
  - Marcha por la justicia., January 1971.; Item No. 5 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    Two-page flier advertising a Chicano Moratorium Committee demonstration against police brutality in the Los Angeles barrios.
  - El Calendario Chicano., 1976 1976.; Item No. 1 (Box 199, Folder 1)
  - El arte de nuestra gente, Centro Hispano de Pacific Bell: Cosmic Rage., c1992.; Item No. 2 (Box 199, Folder 1)
- Mexican-Americans - California - Los Angeles (Box 222)
- Middletown, California (Box 271)
- Miles, Josephine, 1911 - (Box 68)
- Military education - California (Box 68)
- Mill Valley and Mt. Tamalpais Scenic Railway (Box 214)
- Mill Valley, California (Box 222)
- Millard, Alice (Parsons), 1873 - 1938 (Box 68)
- Miller, Henry, 1891 - (Boxes 211, 226, 262)
  Box 211 - 2 folders.
  Box 226 is an oversize flat box, 21" x 25". Box 262 is an oversize flat box, 22-1/2" x 28-1/2".
- Miller, Joaquin (Box 68)
- Miller, John Franklin, 1831 - 1886 (Box 68)
- Millikan, Robert Andrews, 1868 - 1953 (Box 68)
  1. Millikan, Robert Andrews, 1868 - 1953 - portrait.
- Mills College. Oakland, California (Box 170)
- Mills, Benjamin Fay, 1857 - 1916 (Box 170)
- Mills, Mary Russell (Hill) [Mrs. Benjamin Fay Mills] (Box 170)
- Mills, Walter Thomas, 1856 - 1912 (Box 170)
- Mills, William Harrison, 1836 - 1907 (Box 170)
- Mines and mineral resources - California (Box 170)
- Miniature golf (Box 284)
- Minorities - Puerto Ricans in California (Box 170)
- Mira Loma, California (Box 244)
- Mission Pak Co. (Box 192)
- Mission San Gabriel Archangel (San Gabriel, California) (Box 284)
- Missions - California (Boxes 69, 190, 244, 255, 261, 262)
  X. Missions - California. X. Spanish missions of California.
  Folder 3 (of 3) missing from box 69, 8/91. Additional material in oversize box 190. Box 255 is an oversize flat box, 21" x 25." Box 261 is an oversize flat box, 21" x 25".
  - Mission La Purisima Concepcion: a glance through its history and the story of its restoration., ca. 1938-1939.; Item No. 1 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    A brief account of the history of the mission and the region, highlighting the 1938 restoration of the original buildings.
- Missions - La Purisima Concepcion Mission. Lompoc, California (Box 69)
- Missions - Nuestra Senora de Los Angeles Church - Los Angeles (Box 69)
  sl card - Asistencia de Mission San Gabriel.
- Missions - Nuestra Senora Delorsisma Soledad Mission (Box 69)
- Missions - San Antonio de Padua Mission (Box 70)
  - Mission San Antonio: the peace and beauty of early California days., ca. 1956.; Item No. 1 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    An account of the history and restoration of the Mission San Antonio de Padua building.
- Missions - San Antonio de Pala Mission (Box 70)
- Missions - San Buenaventura Mission (Box 70)
  - Mission San Buena Ventura: one hundred and seventy-fifth anniversary., 1957.; Item No. 1 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    A brief history of the San Buenaventura Mission, including a program for Mass celebrating its 175th anniversary.
- Missions - San Carlos Borromeo Mission (Box 70)
- Missions - San Diego de Alcala Mission (Box 70)
  - The mother mission: San Diego de Alcala., ca. 1934.; Item No. 1 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    A brief account of the history of the San Diego Mission.
- Missions - San Fernando Rey de Espaa Mission (Boxes 70, 262)
  - San Fernando Rey: the mission of the valley., 1932.; Item No. 1 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    An account of the history of the Mission San Fernando, Rey de Espaa building.
  - Two big nights: Prayer of the Padre annual pageant., 1933.; Item No. 2 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    Brochure advertising a pagaent entitled "Prayer of the Padre," a historical drama staged to raise funds for the restoration of the San Fernando Mission, Rey de Espaa.
- Missions - San Francisco de Assisi Mission (Boxes 70, 199)
- Missions - San Francisco de Solano Mission (Box 70)
- Missions - San Jose de Guadalupe Mission (Box 70)
- Missions - San Juan Bautista Mission (Box 70)
- Missions - San Juan Capistrano Mission (Box 70)
  - Mission San Juan Capistrano., ca. 1926.; Item No. 1 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    Pamphlet of photographs documenting the Mission San Juan Capistrano in the early 1920s.
- Missions - San Luis Obispo Mission (Box 71)
- Missions - San Luis Rey de Francia Mission (Box 71)
- Missions - San Miguel Mission (Box 71)
- Missions - San Rafael Archangel Mission (Box 71)
- Missions - Santa Barbara Mission (Box 71)
- Missions - Santa Clara Mission (Box 71)
- Missions - Santa Cruz Mission (Box 71)
- Missions - Santa Ines Mission (Box 71)
- Mitchell Caverns State Reserve - California (Box 271)
- Mobile homes (Box 190)
- Mobile homes - California (Box 211)
- Mobilization for Democracy. Los Angeles. (Box 71)
- Model ships (Box 271)
- Model trains (Box 271)
- Modjeska, Helena, 1840 - 1909 (Box 71)
  1. Modjeska, Helena, 1840 - 1909 - portrait.
- Modoc County, California (Box 71)
- Moffett, William Andrew, 1933 - 1995 (Box 211)
- Mojave Desert, California (Boxes 71, 261)
- Mojave National Preserve (Box 225)
- Monette, Paul (Box 271)
- Money, William, ca. 1807 - 1880 (Box 71)
- Monlux, John B. (Box 71)
  1. Monlux, John B. - portrait.
- Mono County, California (Box 71)
- Monrovia, California (Box 71)
- Monsen, Frederick Inman, 1865 - 1929 (Box 71)
- Montebello, California (Box 244)
- Montecito, California (Box 271)
- Monterey County, California (Box 72)
- Monterey Park, California (Box 72)
  Ramona Acres, Calif.
- Monterey, California (Boxes 72, 244)
  Monterey, Calif. - views.
- Montgomery, George, 1847 - 1907 (Box 72)
- Moon, Carl, 1878 - 1948 (Box 72)
- Mooney, Thomas J., 1882 - 1942 (Box 72)
- Moore, Ernest Carroll, 1871 - 1955 (Box 72)
- Moorpark College. Moorpark, California (Box 244)
- Moorpark, California (Box 284)
- Morales family (Box 72)
  1. Morales, Diego, 1852? -.
- Morgan Hill, California (Box 284)
- Morgan, Julia, 1872 - 1957 (Box 72)
  X. Women as architects. 1. Women architects.
- Mormon Island, California (Box 72)
- Morongo Band of Mission Indians. Banning, California (Box 284)
- Morongo Valley, California (Box 211)
- Morris, Wright, 1910 - (Box 72)
- Morro Bay, California (Box 72)
  1. Morro Bay, Calif - views.
- Morse, Willard Samuel, 1856 - 1935 (Box 72)
- Mortuaries - California (Box 72)
- Motels - California (Box 211)
- Mother Lode Country, California (Box 72)
  1. Boynton, Ray, 1883 - 1951.
- Motion picture industry - California (Box 211)
- Motion Picture Relief Fund, Inc. (Box 186)
- Motion picture theaters - California - Los Angeles (Box 192)
- Motion picture theatres - California (Box 244)
- Motion pictures - California - marketing (Box 72)
- Motion pictures - Societies, etc. (Box 244)
- Mott, John Griffin, 1874 - 1942 (Box 72)
- Mount Baldy, California (Boxes 214, 244)
- Mount Lowe, California (Boxes 73, 197, 213, 214)
  Box 73 - 2 folders. Box 73 is an oversize box 197.
  Box 197 is an oversize flat box. Box 213 is an oversize flat box, 15" x 19".
- Mount Washington, California (Los Angeles County) (Box 195)
- Mount Whitney Club. Visalia, California (Box 73)
- Muir Woods National Monument (Box 73)
- Muir, John, 1838 - 1914 (Box 73)
- Mulholland, William, 1855 - 1935 (Box 73)
- Municipal League of Los Angeles (Box 73)
- Mural painting and decoration - California - Los Angeles (Box 196)
- Murphy, Franklin David, 1916 - (Boxes 73, 211)
- Murray, Hugh Campbell, 1825 - 1857 (Box 74)
- Murray, Neil Randall, 1889 - 1959 (Box 74)
- Murrieta Hot Springs, California (Box 261)
- Museum of Contemporary Art (Los Angeles, California.)
  See:: Los Angeles, Calif. Museum of Contemporary Art.
- Museum of Flying. Santa Monica, California (Box 211)
- Museum of Latin American Art. Long Beach, California (Box 244)
- Museum of Television and Radio. Beverly Hills, California (Box 244)
- Museum of Tolerance. Los Angeles, California.
  SEE: Simon Wisenthal Center. Los Angeles, Calif.
- Museums - California (Box 244)
- Music - California - Los Angeles (Box 171)
- Music - Instruction and study (Box 271)
- Music - Performance (Box 284)
- Music, popular (songs, etc.) - California (Box 171)
  Also oversize material.
- Music-halls (variety-theatres, cabarets, etc.) - Los Angeles (Box 171)
  2 folders. X. Night clubs. X. Cabarets.. X. Variety-theatres.
- Muybridge, Eadweard, 1830 - 1904 (Box 74)
- Naegele, George Herman, 1887? - 1942 (Box 74)
- Nahl, Charles Christian, 1818 - 1878 (Box 74)
- Names, geographical - California, Southern (Box 74)
  1. Place names - California, Southern.
- Napa County, California (Boxes 74, 225)
- Napa, California (Box 244)
- Nathan, Robert, 1894 - (Box 74)
  1. Nathan, Robert, 1894 - - portrait.
- National Citizens Political Action Committee. Southern California Chapter. 64th Assembly District. (Box 74)
- National Citizens Political Action Committee. Southern California Chapter. Action for Today. (Box 74)
- National Citizens Political Action Committee. Southern California Chapter. Executive Board. (Box 74)
- National Citizens Political Action Committee. Southern California Chapter. Financial statements. (Box 74)
- National Citizens Political Action Committee. Southern California Chapter. Letters to members. (Box 74)
- National Citizens Political Action Committee. Southern California Chapter. Meetings. (Box 74)
- National Citizens Political Action Committee. Southern California Chapter. Membership. (Box 74)
- National Citizens Political Action Committee. Southern California Chapter. Miscellaneous. (Box 74)
- National Citizens Political Action Committee. Southern California Chapter. Organizations, etc. (Box 74)
- National Citizens Political Action Committee. Southern California Chapter. Reports. (Box 74)
- National Japanese American Historical Society (Box 74)
- National Lawyers Guild of Los Angeles (Box 74)
- National Marrow Donor Program (Southern California) (Box 284)
- National Multiple Sclerosis Society (Southern California) (Box 284)
- Native Daughters of the Golden West (Box 74)
- Nava, Julian (Box 192)
- Needham, James Carson, 1864 - (Box 74)
- Needles, California (Box 189)
- Negroes - California (Box 74)
  - National Negro Congress. Bay District Conference., April 18, 1936.; Item No. 1 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    Program for the 1936 Bay District Conference of the National Negro Congress. Speakers include Ishmael P. Flory, Augustus Hawkins, Paul Radin, and Vernon Gray.
  - Midnite Variety Show., May 1, 1937.; Item No. 2 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    Program for the Midnite Variety Show at the Gateway Theatre in Oakland, featuring African American performers. Program was sponsored by the National Negro Congress, East Bay Council, and features a list of patrons including local businesses.
  - Kenneth Spencer: presented by East Bay Council of the National Negro Congress., September 11, 1936.; Item No. 3 (Folder 1)
    Program for an evening performance by Kenneth Spencer, a classically trained bass baritone singer and actor. Sponsored by the National Negro Congress, the program contains a brief essay on the mission of that organization and numerous advertisements from local businesses.
- Neighborhood Adult Participation Project (Box 192)
- Neighborhood Youth Association. Los Angeles, California. (Box 211)
- Neptune Society. Burbank, California (Box 244)
- Nethery, Wallace (Box 222)
- Neutra, Richard Joseph, 1892 - (Boxes 75, 197, 244)
- Nevada City, California (Box 189)
- New Almaden Quicksilver Mines, California (Box 75)
- New West (Box 75)
- Newark, Alameda County, California (Box 75)
- Newhall, California (Los Angeles County, California) (Box 75)
- Newmark, Marco R., 1878 - 1959 (Box 75)
- Newport Beach, California (Boxes 75, 244, 284)
- Newport Beach, California - maps (Box 261)
- Neylan, John Francis, 1885 - 1960 (Box 75)
- Niemeyer, Atalus, 1868? - 1942 (Box 75)
- Nightclubs (Box 271)
- Nipton, California (Box 271)
- Non profit organizations - California (Box 192)
- Norco, California (Box 271)
- Nordhoff, California (Box 75)
- Nordhoff, Walter, 1858 - 1937 (Box 75)
- Norris, Frank, 1870 - 1902 (Box 75)
- Norris, Kathleen (Thompson), 1880 - 1966 (Box 75)
- North American Blueberry Council. Folsom, California (Box 211)
  X. Blueberries.
- North Hollywood, California (Box 261)
- North of Bay Counties Association (Box 75)
  Includes Del Norte, Humboldt, Lake, Marin, Mendocino, Napa and Sonoma counties.
- Norton Simon Museum. Pasadena, California (Box 271)
- Norton, Joshua A. (Emperor), 1819 - 1880 (Box 75)
  X. Emperor Jones.
- Nosotros. Los Angeles, California. (Box 284)
- Novato, California (Box 271)
- Nurseries - California - Los Angeles (Box 222)
- Nutrition (Box 211)
- Oakland, California (Boxes 172, 197, 284)
  Also shelved oversize.
- Occidental College (Box 75)
- Occult sciences (Box 75)
- Ocean liners (Box 244)
- Ocean Park, California (Box 75)
- Oceanside, California (Boxes 75, 271)
- O'Dea, Michael Francis, 1848? - 1938 (Box 75)
- O'Holloran, Rose (Box 75)
- Oil Companies - California (Box 271)
- Ojai Valley (Box 222)
- Ojai, California (Boxes 75, 190, 261, 284)
  Also oversize box 190.
- OLAM. Los Angeles, California. (Box 251)
- Old Age Pension Agitation Collection (Box 172)
- Old Gabriel (Box 172)
  1. Indians of North America, new southwest. X. Gabriel, Old.
- Olesen Lighting Co. Los Angeles, California. (Box 130)
  1. Oleson, Otto K. 2. Moving picture industry. X. Otto K. Oleson Co.
- Olesen, William L. (Box 172)
  "Harbor memories", 10 articles in the San Pedro News-Pilot, Mar. 7 - Dec. 1, 1970.
  1. SAN PEDRO, CALIF. - HISTORY. 2. LOS ANGELES - HARBOR.
- Olson, Culbert L. (Box 172)
- Olympic Games. Los Angeles, 1984. (Box 131)
  Oversize flat box.
- O'Melveny, Donald, 1891 - 1942 (Box 172)
- O'Melveny, Henry Williams, 1859 - 1941 (Box 172)
- Ontario, California (Box 172)
- Opera - California - Los Angeles (Box 244)
- Optometry colleges (Box 284)
- Orange County Transportation Authority. Orange County, California (Boxes 244, 271)
- Orange County, California (Boxes 76, 199, 244, 284)
  Box 76 - 2 folders. Also shelved oversize.
- Orange County, California - Community organizations (Box 76)
- Orange County, California - Description and travel (Box 76)
- Orange County, California - Museums (Box 222)
- Orange County, California - Transportation (Box 76)
- Orange Empire Railway Museum. Perris, California (Boxes 189, 284)
- Orange, California (Box 189)
- Orb Foundation. Los Angeles, California. (Box 76)
- Orchestras - California - Los Angeles (Box 244)
- Orcutt, William Warren, 1869 - 1942 (Box 76)
- Organic to Go. Los Angeles, California. (Box 284)
- Orland, California (Glenn County) (Box 172)
- Ornamental Iron Manufacturers Association of Southern California. SEE ORION.
  Cataloged in Orion. August 1995.
- Oroville, California (Box 76)
- Orphanos, Stathis, 1945 - (Box 76)
  Ontario Review, no. 18 (Spring/Summer 1983) "Out to OID, 4/96/dl." missing 5/6/2003.
- Ortega family (Box 76)
- Otis Art Institute. Los Angeles, California. (Box 186)
- Otis, Eliza Ann (Wetherby), 1833 - 1904 (Box 172)
- Otis, Harrison Gray, 1837 - 1917 (Box 172)
- Ouspenskaya, Maria (Box 211)
- Outfest. West Hollywood, California (Boxes 245, 284)
- Owens Valley, California (Boxes 76, 253)
  See: INYO REGISTER AND OWENS VALLEY HERALD.
- Oxnard, California (Boxes 76, 245)
- Pacheco family (Box 76)
- Pacheco, Romualdo, 1831 - 1899 (Box 76)
  1. Pacheco, Romualdo, 1831 - 1899 - portrait.
- Pacific Electric Railway (Box 253)
- Pacific Electric Railway Company (Boxes 76, 253)
  1. Tilton's Trolley Trip. "Map of Pacific Electric Railway and Motor Transit System in Southern California, May 1930"
- Pacific Gas and Electric Co. (Box 192)
- Pacific Geographic Society. Los Angeles, California. (Box 77)
- Pacific Grove, California (Box 77)
  1. Asilomar Hotel and Conference Grounds.
- Pacific Palisades, California (Boxes 77, 284)
  1. BERNHEIMER ORIENTAL GARDENS. PACIFIC PALISADES, CALIF.
- Pacificulture - Asia Museum. Pasadena, California (Box 77)
- Packard, William, 1803 - 1977 (Box 77)
- Padua Hills Theater (Box 77)
- Pageants - California (Box 77)
- Paine, Edward W. (Box 77)
- Paine, Nathan (Box 77)
  1. PAINE, NATHAN - PORTRAIT
- Pala, California (San Diego County) (Box 77)
- Palevsky, Joan (Box 77)
- Palm Desert, California (Boxes 245, 272)
- Palm Springs, California (Boxes 78, 261, 272)
  Box 272 - 2 folders.
- Palm Springs, California - Hotels, taverns, etc. (Box 78)
- Palmdale, California (Box 211)
  X Pottery
- Palmer, Phil (Box 222)
- Palo Alto, California (Box 245)
- Palomar Mountain (Box 78)
- Palomar Observatory (Box 78)
- Palomares family (Box 78)
  1. PALOMARES, YGNACIO, 1862? - 1949
- Palos Verdes Estates, California (Box 78)
- Pan-Pacific Auditorium (Box 78)
- Paradise, California (Box 78)
- Paramount Pictures. Hollywood, California (Box 245)
- Pardee, George Cooper, 1857 - 1941 (Box 78)
- Parenting (Box 272)
- Parks - California (Box 78)
- Parks - California, Southern (Box 78)
- Parrott, John, 1811 - 1884 (Box 78)
- Pasadena Art Institute. Pasadena, California (Box 285)
- Pasadena Art Museum. Pasadena, California (Box 285)
- Pasadena Heritage (Box 80)
- Pasadena Playhouse. Pasadena, California (Box 272)
- Pasadena Tournament of Roses. Pasadena, California (Box 80)
- Pasadena, California (Boxes 79, 214, 285)
  1. SAN RAFAEL AREA. PASADENA, CALIF.
- Pasadena, California - Busch Gardens (Box 79)
- Pasadena, California - Hotels, taverns, etc. (Boxes 79, 251, 285)
  1. RAYMOND HOTEL. PASADENA, CALIF.
- Pasadena, California - Residences (Box 173)
- Pasadena, California Rialto Theater. (Box 173)
- Pasadena, California - Schools (Box 173)
- Paso Robles, California (Boxes 80, 251)
- Patchen, Kenneth, 1911 - (Box 80)
- Patterson, California (Box 80)
- Patterson, Wilson Campbell (Box 80)
- Patton, George Smith, 1885 - 1945 (Box 80)
- Pauley, Edwin (Box 285)
- Payne, Theodore (Box 189)
- Peano, Felix, 18- - 1948 (Box 80)
- Pearlberg, Irving (Box 80)
- Peebles, James Martin, 1822 - 1922 (Box 80)
  1. PEEBLES, JAMES MARTIN, 1822 - 1922 - PORTRAIT
- Peixotto, Sidney Salzado, 1866 - 1925 (Box 80)
- PEN (Organization) (Box 272)
- Performance art - California - Los Angeles (Box 189)
- Performing arts - California - Los Angeles (Boxes 192, 245)
- Performing arts festivals - California - Los Angeles (Box 80)
- Performing arts sponsorship - California (Box 80)
- Periodicals - California (Box 80)
- Perkins, George Clement, 1839 - 1923 (Box 80)
- Personals (Box 245)
- Pescadero, California (Box 285)
- Pet Health - California (Box 285)
- Pet stores - California (Box 245)
- Petaluma, California (Boxes 80, 285)
  1. TAYLOR, BAYARD, 1825 - 1878
- Petroleum industry and trade - California (Boxes 174, 255)
- Pets - California (Box 80)
- Pharmacies - California (Box 245)
- Phelan, James Duval, 1861 - 1930 (Box 80)
- Philosophical Research Society. Los Angeles, California. (Boxes 81, 245)
- Photography - California (Boxes 175, 214, 245)
  Box 175 - 4 folders.
- Photography - California - Exhibitions (Boxes 82, 197)
- Physical fitness - California (Box 222)
- Pickford, Mary, 1893 - (Box 81)
- Pico Rivera, California (Box 211)
- Pico, Pio, 1801 - 1894 (Box 81)
- Pierce, Charles C. (Box 81)
- Pierce, Herbert Augustus, 1856? - 1942 (Box 81)
- Pinnacles National Monument. San Benito County, California (Box 81)
- Pioneers - San Bernardino, California (Box 83)
  Historical series, "History in the making," by L. Burr Belden, in San Bernardino Sun-Telgram.
  Apr. 1, 1951 - Sept. 20, 1953. Gift of Mrs. William Beatty. See shelf list for subject and added entries.
- Pioneers - San Francisco (Box 83)
  Box 83 - 3 folders.
  X SAN FRANCISCO - PIONEERS
- Pioneertown, California (Box 285)
- Pious Fund of the Californias (Box 285)
- Pismo Beach, California (Box 245)
- Placer County, California (Box 83)
  X PLACER COUNTY CITRUS COLONY
- Placerita Canyon, California (Box 83)
  1. MINES AND MINERAL RESOURCES - CALIFORNIA
- Planned Parenthood. Los Angeles, California. (Boxes 211, 285)
- Playa Del Rey, California (Boxes 83, 285)
- Playa Vista (Development). Playa Vista, California (Boxes 211, 226, 231, 257, 272)
  Box 231 - Ballona Free Press, April 1999 issue (#11). Box 257 - 3 folders.
- Pleasanton, California (Boxes 83, 285)
- Pleasants, Ben. (Box 272)
- Poetry readings - California (Box 189)
- Poetry Society of Southern California. The Historian. (Box 83)
  vol. 1, no. 1-12. July 16, 1950 - June 17, 1951.
- Poets of California (Box 84)
- Point Reyes, California (Box 84)
- Politicians - Newsletters (Box 84)
- Pollution (Box 272)
- Pomona College. Claremont, California (Box 84)
- Pomona, California (Box 84)